[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
[Julio] I'm here to make you
an offer, Ivy.
-A hundred million pesos.
-In exchange for?
Get back together with my grandson.
[Camia] What are you going to do?
Help Arnaldo recover
right after having him jailed?
Arnaldo is the weakness of the Ardientes--
Emilia, Raul, and especially Julio.
So I need Arnaldo to finish off
the Ardientes once and for all.
[Julio] Ivy Aguas' funeral is
postponed until further notice.
[screaming]
-[Raul] What's going on?
-Nothing!
I need a man who is my equal,
and that obviously isn't you!
[Raul] Well then, let's split up already!
[Julio] Your son needs you
all the more right now!
And I don't want the public to know
that this family is already falling apart!
[Camia] Mayor Arnaldo's release
is a slap in the face
to the people of Poblacion Ardiente.
Only one man has the right
to lead Poblacion Ardiente.
That's Diego Torillo.
[supporters] Diego Torillo for change!
Let the games begin!
[Ivy] You just think you've won, Emilia.
But it was all part of my plan.
Ivy's here. When you find her, kill her.
We'll make it look like an accident.
[tires screeching]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Emilia shrieking]
You-- Ivy!
Where were you?!
Look, she's escaped! Ouch!
-[groans]
-[woman] Emilia, what happened?!
Guard, where are
the surveillance cameras here?
This way, ma'am.
I'll make sure that woman pays for this!
[growls]
[tense music playing]
[ominous music playing]
[Jaguar] We can't be sure yet
of Diego's victory in the election.
The Ardientes will do everything
in their power to make sure
that their territory
doesn't fall into enemy hands.
Boss, how can Mayor Arnaldo
still win at this point?
He's gone insane.
A lot of people have lost their sanity
after being elected in this town.
I've yet to hear a corpse
getting elected though.
But that just might happen to Diego…
if you fail to protect him.
If we fail to protect him!
I must acquire the Ardientes'
power at all costs.
And that'll only happen
if Diego wins the election.
If you manage to protect him, that is.
Madrigal…
You'll be my eyes
and ears in Diego's camp.
Make sure nothing bad happens
to him, or else, it's on you.
Leave it to me, boss. As you wish.
[tense music playing]
Looks like there's no footage
of the culprit, ma'am Emilia.
Whoever did this planned
everything in advance.
They knew where
the camera's blind spots were,
and how to avoid the guards.
There's no proof it was Ivy Aguas.
[grunts]
[breathing heavily]
[guard] We're sorry, ma'am.
[lamp switch flicking]
Arnaldo.
Arnal--
Arnaldo…
Arnaldo, what are you doing there?
[lamp switch flicking]
Arnaldo, come here.
Arnaldo, it's me, your grandfather.
Come here and take your medicine.
Come on.
This is me, your Grandpa Julio.
Come here. Take your medicine.
That's it.
Come on, son.
Please.
That's it.
Take your medicine. This is good for you.
Hmm?
[somber music playing]
Arnaldo, Arnaldo!
Arnaldo! Arnaldo!
-Arnaldo, that's enough!
-[chuckling]
-Arnaldo…
You're not insane.
You're not crazy. Do you hear me?
I won't let you go insane.
I made you a god of this place.
I won't let you throw away
everything I've done for you.
Arnaldo…
[singing indistinctly]
Arnaldo, please.
Do you hear me?
[pills clatter softly]
I… V… Y…
A… G… U…
…as.
I… V…
Y…
-Y…
-[Julio sighs]
Aguas. [laughing]
I! V! Y!
A! G! U! A! S!
Enough… Enough!
Enough…
-You'll come back.
-That's enough, Arnaldo.
You'll come back to me.
-[sniffles]
-[Arnaldo] A…
This is my fault.
-G… U…
-It's my fault.
[whispering] A… G…
U… A…
S…
I… V…
[chortles]
Please, stop it…
[chortling continues]
-Damn you, Ivy!
-[chortling continues]
Damn you, Ivy Aguas!
-What have you done to my son?
-[chortling continues]
I'm not done with you, Ivy!
I am not yet done with you.
[tense music playing]
Dear.
[somber music playing]
I'm sure the Ardientes
are already coming up
with a way to silence you.
I'm not afraid of them at all.
And I don't have to hide
behind you, either.
Don't go back to the Ardientes anymore.
Let me fight against them now.
Please, come home.
Mom, I'm sorry.
But I'll be able to protect you more
if I stay close with the Ardientes.
[pensive music playing]
Mayor, I brought you some food.
Mayor?
-[ominous music playing]
-[plates and utensils clatter]
Mayor!
Ma'am Emilia!
-Ma'am Emilia!
-Arnaldo?!
[house help] Ma'am!
-What happened?!
-Ma'am Emilia!
-What's going on?!
-Arnaldo!
[ominous music playing]
[Julio] What happened?!
[shrieking]
[both shrieking]
Arnaldo! Arnaldo!
[shrieking]
Arnaldo!
[Raul] Help! Papa!
-[gunshots]
-[Raul] Son!
Son! [screams]
Arnaldo!
-[Emilia wails]
-[Raul screams]
[Raul] Arnaldo!
-[Emilia sobs] Arnaldo!
-[Raul] Help!
Help…
-[Raul screams]
-[Emilia wailing]
-[Raul] Arnaldo! Help!
Son!
[desolate music playing]
[Emilia wailing]
[Raul] Son!
Son!
[Emilia wailing]
Arnaldo…
Why? Why?
-[Raul] Get help!
-Why?
[sobbing] Arnaldo!
-Please! Get help!
-[Emilia] Arnaldo!
-[Raul] Son? Arnaldo!
Arnaldo!
[desolate music playing]
Miss Ivy?
Please wait here.
I'll call the congressman.
What happened?
Excuse me. [sniffles]
[desolate music playing]
[Julio sniffling]
[foreboding music playing]
[whimpering]
[sobbing]
[stirring music playing]
[sobs] Look. Look…
Look what happened to Arnaldo…
Look what happened to my grandson!
He hung himself! [sobs]
[tense music playing]
[sobbing]
Who did this to you?!
Who?! [wailing]
Mark my words,
you'll meet the same fate
as Nanny Carlotta did.
I'll make you suffer so much
you'll want to kill yourself.
He hung himself, Ivy… He hung himself.
[Julio sobbing]
Why? Why?
Why did he do it?
[sobbing]
[sobs]
Why…
Why?
[sobbing continues]
[sobs] My poor grandson…
I'm not an evil person.
But your family drove me
to become like this.
I must put an end to your cruelty…
so that no one else will have to
experience hell at your hands.
This is the only law I know…
Do not do unto others
what you don't want others to do unto you.
[sobbing]
[tense music playing]
[sniffles]
[whimpering]
No respectable man
is ever prepared for the worst
that can happen
to his flesh and blood.
Ivy, Arnaldo is in the hospital…
He's in the hospital
and he's fighting for his life!
[sobbing]
[Emilia] Arnaldo!
[Claire] Don't worry… He'll be fine.
[screams] Where's the doctor?! Doctor!
[Raul] Doc, this is an emergency!
Please attend to my son!
Doc, please do everything to save our son!
[sobbing]
[Emilia sobbing]
Arnaldo! [sobbing]
-[doctor] Check vitals.
-Yes, doc.
[sobbing] Arnaldo…
You mean… Arnaldo's still alive?
But he's fighting for his life!
Do you understand?!
He's fighting for his life!
[Julio sobbing]
[tense music playing]
You know, Auntie,
even if Arnaldo and I
don't always get along,
he's still my son and I'm going
to do everything to protect him.
We just need to trust and believe
that Arnaldo can survive
all of this. Okay?
[tense music playing]
You!
Emilia, don't. Don't.
What makes you think for
a second that I won't find out
the little stunt that you pulled?
You have some nerve. Stay there!
I have no time to fight.
I'm here for Arnaldo.
You tormented him. You left him!
And now you're visiting him?
You have some nerve, huh?!
Get out.
-Get--
-Don't touch me.
Emilia?
Don't you dare go near my son.
We aren't done yet.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia shrieking]
[Raul] Arnaldo!
[gunshot]
Arnaldo! Son!
[unsettling music playing]
[phone ringing]
[phone continues ringing]
Mayor Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo
was rushed to the hospital
earlier this afternoon
due to unknown reasons.
According to witnesses,
the mayor was unconscious
when he was rushed
to the Ardiente Medical Center.
We have yet to confirm
the mayor's condition…
What kind of stunt is this?
[reporter] Will the mayor
soon give up his campaign
and let his brother, Diego, win?
We'll return for more updates.
This is Dennis Pangilinan, reporting.
[Julio] No way in hell
will I allow a bastard like Diego
to think that he can defeat Arnaldo.
Ardientes are born winners.
An Ardiente never dies!
An Ardiente never loses or accepts defeat.
[tense music playing]
[clatters]
Arnaldo's hanging was near fatal.
It's lucky that you found him right away.
Doc, can we see him?
The patient is still in critical care.
His airway is secured by intubation.
We will perform some tests to make sure
the patient didn't sustain
any major injuries.
Thank you, doc.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
That's good news.
[tense music playing]
[sighs]
[door opens]
[monitor beeping rhythmically]
[ominous music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
Do you want me to pity you?
My heart is incapable
of pitying you though.
Because every time I look at you…
I remember all the things you've done.
So, even if I want you to experience
all the pain you've inflicted
on my loved ones
and to all the families you've ruined…
I can't let you die just yet.
Because you don't deserve to die, Arnaldo.
You deserve a fate worse than death.
[suspenseful music playing]
You need to live.
Because I'm not done with you yet.
I'm not through with the Ardientes.
Get that Ivy Aguas out of my son's room!
I don't want to see her!
-I want her out of my sight now!
-[Julio] Emilia!
How could you be so careless?!
Now the whole world knows
what happened to Arnaldo!
-Papa, I banned the media here!
-[chuckles]
I got news for you!
The news was leaked and it
landed on national television!
Miss Aguas, please come with me.
No, I'll stay with Arnaldo.
But Miss Emilia doesn't want you in here--
I don't care.
You truly are useless.
Useless?
I'm the one who's useless, Papa?
Who was with Arnaldo while
he was hanging for his life?
When he was being revived? It was me!
And you tell me I'm useless?
This is all your fault, Papa!
[Julio] I have never…
nor will I ever do anything
that will ruin my grandson.
Arnaldo will get well
and he will become governor.
Honestly, you're the only one
who's not doing anything for your son
except to usurp his candidacy!
I wanted to run for governor
not because of my ambition,
but because I know
that my son is not well!
He needs to heal and rest!
But what did you do?
You treated him like he just had a fever!
Like he'd get better
just by drinking some medicine!
That's not it, Papa!
You have to accept the fact
that Arnaldo is not well!
You're the one who's killing him--
[Raul] Papa!
-Julio, what are you doing?!
-Shut up, all of you!
No one!
No one tells Julio Ardiente what to do!
You know why I'm forcing Arnaldo
to get over this temporary
mental incapacity?
It's because if I were to leave it to you,
we wouldn't gain anything!
The Ardientes wouldn't
accomplish anything!
You entourage of freeloaders!
And you!
Get your filthy hands off her,
and wrap those fingers
around the neck of the person
who ordered you to throw Ivy Aguas out!
Ivy Aguas is here to stay at my behest!
That's the end of this conversation!
[tense music playing]
Emilia, let's go.
Auntie, does Ivy know
what happened to Arnaldo?
Diego, Lily returned to the Ardientes.
What?!
She needs to finish what she started,
even if it means putting off our reunion.
[sighs] Auntie, I don't want to
lose faith in Ivy's decisions.
But it's too dangerous!
What if this time, she can't
escape the Ardientes anymore?
[sighs]
She always puts her life in danger.
Has it ever happened in your life…
that you felt your life
was being toyed around
by some unseen force…
and you felt so helpless
that you couldn't do anything?
[tense music playing]
I have.
Lots of times, Congressman.
In our lives,
some things happen
when you least expect them to.
That's why, you take control
of the situation,
and use it to your advantage.
What about you, Congressman?
[sighs]
Never.
[chuckles] That has never
happened to me before.
[Julio inhales sharply]
They say that all the
wrong things you've done
will come back to you.
Well, I spit on karma's grave.
I have the power.
Karma has always been
just a concept in my life…
…until now.
I will face anything or anyone.
Even the Devil himself.
I will face him and say,
"You can take my life…
in exchange for Arnaldo's."
[monitor beeping rhythmically]
[somber music playing]
I can't believe the gut of that witch!
She has the nerve to come here
after everything she did to Arnaldo!
How shameless! She even
got Papa under her spell!
Maybe Ivy is just worried about Arnaldo.
Those two loved each other back then.
So maybe we could cut Ivy some slack,
and give her another chance for Arnaldo.
Hold on.
Are you sure you're referring
to Ivy and Arnaldo?
Because I don't have the time
to listen to your drama, Raul.
That Ivy… [scoffs]
Everything is her fault.
She put Arnaldo under her spell
until he went crazy.
I know it.
But I promise you,
she'll never be able
to set foot in our house.
[exhales] She'll pay for everything.
Raul, please!
You know, Congressman…
Arnaldo is very important to me.
So, while you're here in the hospital…
I will stay with you…
until he recovers.
I have decided.
I will get back together with Arnaldo.
And I will take care of him.
[sniffles]
Then--Then I will have the money prepared.
But, wait…
You haven't told me which
position you're interested in.
Livelihood? Uh, health?
Miss Aguas…
Julio Ardiente always keeps his promises.
I know that.
But Arnaldo is more important to me.
I don't need money
or any government position.
Do you mean to tell me…
love is a good enough reason for you?
[inhales sharply]
Arnaldo is important to me…
so I will take care of him.
[tense music playing]
I lied, pretended, and made
heavy choices out of anger.
But we're still different
when it comes to who or what we turn to.
May my loved ones forgive and guide me…
because I will never give up this fight.
Ivy Aguas comes home with us tonight.
[tense music playing]
[sighs]
Grandpa, wait for me.
[tense music playing]
[reporter 1] Congressman, any
statement about what happened?
-What can you say?
-I have nothing to say.
[reporter 1] How's your family doing?
Miss Ivy Aguas, are you
and the mayor on good terms?
I'm sorry, not now.
[reporter 2] Miss Emilia, what
happened to your son, Arnaldo?
Well, yes. It's true
that something happened to him.
The worst thing that can happen
to a mother in distress…
A snake has entered our home.
Emilia.
-[camera shutter clicks]
-I need to ask you something.
[reporter 1] Wait!
When will he leave the hospital?
-[reporter 2] Sir, a statement?
-[reporter 1] Wait!
What was that?!
Was that on purpose, Emilia?!
You're doing this on purpose, Papa!
How can you do this?
How can you let that rat
destroy our family, our home?
Put a lid on it!
Well, it wasn't long ago
that you were so furious with my son!
Even I couldn't believe
the things you said!
That's what you think because
that's what you want to think.
What matters now is Arnaldo.
He's more important than your paranoia.
Or maybe, you want
to follow in his footsteps?
Be careful. You might break.
[scoffs] The nerve!
Papa, how can you protect her like this?
This woman?
She's forcing herself
to be one of us, Papa.
And she's never going
to be one of us, Papa!
Your son needs Ivy.
Without Ivy, Arnaldo will die.
So, if you don't want to lose Arnaldo,
you will kill whatever demons
are whispering in your ears
and you will accept the fact
that Miss Aguas is here to stay.
And you will do that, Emilia…
if you want your son to live.
[tense music playing]
[sighs]
I'm sorry, Congressman.
She never understands anything anyway.
[sighs]
Auntie, does Lily really need
to go back to the Ardientes?
It's dangerous.
She's using herself as bait.
They can't hurt her
or lay a finger on her.
Anna, Lily is smart.
She can manipulate the Ardientes
even if Arnaldo isn't in the mansion.
I'm just concerned, Auntie.
Arnaldo's crimes
have already been made public.
But his case was just dismissed
like it was nothing.
Auntie, don't we have
any chances to fight this?
Fighting the Ardientes isn't that easy.
No.
We need that demon, Arnaldo,
to answer for his crimes.
If not through the law,
then maybe there's another way.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia] So, Ivy…
Since Arnaldo isn't here at the moment…
Are you willing to mingle with us?
[Julio] Emilia…
Now that Miss Aguas is back with us,
I would advise you to bite your tongue
every time you get the urge
to hurl invectives or insults at her.
[scoffs]
Miss Aguas is here as a favor for Arnaldo.
So, please, respect her.
I respect her, Papa.
I just don't like her.
I really do respect you…
to a point where I won't
drag you out of our home.
So, I'll give way.
I'll leave, instead.
Excuse me.
[shrieks] Oh my…
-[house help] I'm so sorry!
-You idiot! Idiot!
-Emilia!
-[Emilia] You idiot!
-Where's your brain, huh?!
-[house help] I'm sorry!
You want this, right? Here, eat it!
-[Raul] Emilia, that's enough.
-[Claire] Emilia!
And always remember,
you don't belong here!
Do you understand?!
-What an idiot.
-That's enough.
[Emilia] This is expensive!
This is worth more than
what you're paid, you idiot!
Go on, Emilia.
Enjoy yourself while you still can
because the day will come
when what I'm going to do
to you will be worse.
I will make you eat dirt.
Dirt.
Anna, I understand how you feel.
But we need to follow
and trust Lily's plans.
Diego, I have a lot of faith in Lily.
There's no doubt about that.
But that faith is clashing
with the thought
that Arnaldo is still alive and free.
Diego, where's the justice in that?
Who said justice was easy to get?
Let me tell you, Anna,
justice isn't something you buy
at a discount.
I crippled Arnaldo.
He isn't free since
he's imprisoned by his insanity.
Now, what are you doing here?
Didn't we have an agreement?
That on the day of my wedding,
you're going to leave.
But I let it go.
Now, what are you still doing here?
I want to trust in your justice, Lily.
But I'm not leaving.
I want to see that justice delivered.
[tense music playing]
Lily, I held myself back.
I didn't say a word
when you kept your plans
for Arnaldo a secret.
Now that you're going after Emilia,
it's my right as your mother
to know about all your plans.
Are you still pursuing them?
Mom, nothing has changed.
I'll pursue my plans for Emilia.
I'll strip her of her wealth
and family name.
Then I'll help you, Lily.
We'll take down Emilia.
I'll help too, Lily.
No, you won't.
Anna, you knew from the start
I was against you being here
because I don't want to put you in danger.
So, I hope you understand.
[tense music playing]
Arnaldo is still alive…
but he's mentally
and emotionally unstable.
I'm sure that the Ardientes
will do everything
for Arnaldo to get well but
I won't make it easy for them.
I won't let Arnaldo
get back on his feet again.
[tense music playing]
[humming]
[foreboding music playing]
Hmm.
Oh, Jaguar…
[exhales]
[line ringing]
Hello, Jaguar?
Hello, Emilia.
You know, you're really full of surprises.
You actually made my day today.
[scoffs] Surprises?
Yeah.
You sent me flowers and I love it.
I'm just wondering how you knew
that roses are my favorite.
I didn't send you flowers.
They're not from me.
What?
They're from Raul?
Hold on. Why do you seem surprised?
Aren't you supposed to be glad?
You told me that you
still love your husband.
Because Raul can't please me with flowers.
Anything that comes from him
is trash, cheap, and ugly!
In fact, I'll throw these
disgusting flowers away.
[tense music playing]
[slams]
[phone vibrating]
Ivy, every second that you're with Arnaldo
is a second less spent with your mother.
Ivy, please stop this.
You're in too deep now.
Diego, taking care of Arnaldo is my key
to gaining access
to the Ardientes' mansion
and pursuing my plans to take down Emilia.
What if he actually gets better
under your care?
I won't let that happen. Never.
I know it's not easy…
and my plans aren't
that clear and perfect,
but I've taken Arnaldo out.
And now, Emilia has to go next.
I won't waste any time
in bringing that woman down.
[sighs]
Just be careful, okay?
Ivy, please take care of yourself.
[unsettling music playing]
[monitor beeping rhythmically]
I have issued a press release
and I'm doing
the necessary damage control.
Thank you for your initiative
and foresight, Miss Aguas.
Emilia…
Why don't you help Miss Aguas
with the damage control
and make yourself useful?
Papa, I'd rather not say anything.
I can't work very well with
people who get on my nerves.
We're on the same side, Emilia.
We both want Arnaldo to recover.
I hope we're on the same page.
[tense music playing]
[reporter] What can you say
about the recent hospitalization
-of Mayor Ardiente?
-[camera shutters click]
I'm saddened by the news about the mayor.
After all, he's my brother.
But that doesn't mean we won't
reopen the lawsuits against him.
Homicide for the murders
of Nimfa, Carlotta,
and Camia Cruz's witnesses.
This is something
we can't take just sitting down.
We'll rise back up
and file the case at a different
court with a different judge.
We won't stop until
Mayor Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo
pays for what he did.
So, to Mayor Arnaldo and his allies,
you may have succeeded
in having the case dismissed,
but that doesn't change the fact
that you're still guilty.
Karma is on our side…
and you'll pay a very high price.
We have some good news.
The results of his tests
and x-ray are normal.
And we'll observe him
for the next 24 hours.
After that, we expect him
to regain full consciousness.
Attaboy, Arnaldo.
You go and fight.
[doctor] And when he wakes up,
we can start his psychiatric
counseling and therapy.
So, in short, doc…
he'll recover easily? I mean…
Is one week good enough
for him to recover?
Papa, Arnaldo needs to pass all his tests…
and get clearance from the doctor.
We do not have the time, Emilia.
He has an election to win.
Doc, maybe it's best…
if you prescribe all the
medicine Arnaldo needs to take.
We are going to make sure
he takes all of it.
Grandpa… I get where you're coming from.
You want Arnaldo
to have a speedy recovery.
But, we need to give him time
to recuperate,
so we can make sure
he'll really win the election.
[tense music playing]
Wait a minute, Emilia.
What's going on?
Do you really want an annulment
while our son's fighting for his life?
Please Raul, can you not use
our son's condition
to settle our problems?
I want an annulment.
To begin with, our marriage is fake.
[scoffs] Why? Who's real to you?
Tell me… Is it Jaguar?
He's just fooling you.
If he really loved you…
he would've fought for you.
You know, Raul, the reason
why you're chasing me
is because somebody else wants me.
After 30 years,
not even once did I feel
you truly loved me, Raul.
Not even once.
So, please, can you not be selfish?
I'm not selfish. That's why I'm trying.
Give me a chance.
Just sign the document.
I want the annulment,
and we're done. It's over.
Damn it.
Hello, Natalie?
[Natalie] Thank goodness.
Finally, you answered my call.
I've been trying to call you
and you don't answer.
-What do you need from me?
-Me? Need something from you?
[sighs] Raul, that's not
the story of our relationship.
It's more of you
needing something from me.
And in this case, I know
you want something from me.
I don't understand.
What are you talking about?
[Natalie] I saw that Arnaldo
is getting sick.
And I'm sure that stresses
you out so much.
So, I'm offering you
a de-stressing kind of session.
Let's not kid ourselves.
This is going once…
twice…
Fine, eight o'clock. The usual place.
I can't wait to see you. Bye!
[tense music playing]
[Ivy] I have information.
And I know you'll be interested.
I will crush that woman into pieces.
-Surprise.
-[chuckles]
-[thwacks]
-[grunts]
[Anna] Do you know how long
I've waited for this opportunity?
Hatred and the need for revenge
can change a person a lot.
You don't know what that person
is capable of.
[Natalie] You think Ivy Aguas
is on your side.
Guess who she's coming after? You!
[tense music playing]
[theme music playing]